dooney.com 2019-06-23

# Dooney & Bourke l Privacy Policy

Dooney & Bourke, Inc. and its affiliated companies (collectively “Dooney”) have created this privacy policy in order to assist you in understanding how we collect and use personal information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our Web Site.

  * What Information Is Collected
  * How We Collect Information
  * How Your Information is Used
  * Shared Information
  * Links To Third-party Websites
  * Information Security
  * Data Retention Periods
  * Other Social Media Websites, Blogs, Message Boards
  * General Audience Website Not Directed Toward Children
  * Access to Personal Information
  * Your California Privacy Rights
  * Consent to Privacy Policy
  * Questions About This Privacy Policy

## What Information Is Collected

The following are the types of information we may collect:

Personally identifiable information is collected when you submit it voluntarily when placing an order or as part of any other communication you may choose to send to Dooney when using our Web Site services. Information you submit may include things such as your name, mailing address, email address, phone number, date of birth, gender, credit card number, and the content of any messages or instructions you may send.

Non-Personal Information:  
At other times, Dooney may collect information such as browser type, Dynamic Host Control Protocol or static (IP) address, “click stream” data, and similar non-personally identifiable information. At times, we may aggregate non-personal information about you and other customers who visit certain areas of our Web Site. These types of information do not generally identify or relate to you as an individual, and we will not seek to associate these types of information with you as an individual. Please understand, however, that others might seek to do so and we cannot guarantee that parties with whom we may share such information will not succeed in re-identifying or associating non-personal information with particular individuals.

We log data on which pages a visitor views, the time spent at our Web Site, the websites visited just before and just after our Web Site, and the advertisements and promotions users view and how they respond to them. This tracking information is used for general Internet tracking and marketing purposes. It is not generally associated with any personally identifiable information.

Further, our online service providers or business partners may implement technologies that allow for the collection of personally identifiable information over time and across websites. We recommend that you review each privacy policy posted on the websites that you visit to better understand privacy practices on those websites. 

While we take all reasonable steps to protect the privacy of our Web Site visitors, we cannot promise that the current limitations of our online applications programming will address every browser setting or honor every personal browser preference. In particular, we have not implemented the necessary program changes to honor “Do Not Track” or “DNT” browser signals. Please return to this privacy policy for further updates on this topic. 

## Electronic Communications

When you open emails from us, our service providers may log and store such information. We may also keep records of various communications regarding the types of products and services that you indicate are of interest to you via your response to email. You will always have the option to opt-out of such communications by clicking an “unsubscribe” link. 

## How We Collect Information 

We may collect information from you in several different areas on the Web Site, including, without limitation, those described below:

Registration:  
You may be asked to complete a registration form and provide personally identifiable information; you may also be asked to choose a userid and password in order to take advantage of certain features on the Web Site or digital messaging services. Your decision to register is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to us and what communications you would like to receive; however, please be advised that some products and services available on the Web Site may require registration and if you elect not to provide such information, you will not be able to take advantage of those products and services.

Cookies and Tracking Technology:  
We may use any number of tools to collect information about you, your computer access points, and the web browser that you use to connect to our Web Site. For example, “cookies” are tiny text files that we place on your computer’s hard drive when you visit our Web Site. We may use cookies to personalize your Web Site experience. You do not have to accept our cookies and you may delete them after they have been placed on your hard drive. If you do not accept or delete our cookies, some areas of our Web Site that you access may take more time to work, or may not function properly. For more information about cookies, visit _[All About Cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)_.

## How Your Information Is Used

We use the information you submit to process your order, provide customer service and make other products and services available to our customers and prospective customers. Occasionally, we may also use the information you submit to notify you about important changes to our Web Site, new services and special offers we think you will find valuable. You will receive e-mails notifying you when products go on sale.

We use your personal information to send you order confirmations. In such cases, you should receive via e-mail an order confirmation within moments of placing your order. From time-to-time you may receive e-mail surveys to rate the quality of products you have purchased, to tell us what improvements to make to Dooney and our services. We may also use your personal information to notify you of special offers. 

Additional uses of your non-personal and personal information will allow us to tailor products and services specific to your needs, to help organize and manage your customer relationship and our business, to conduct business, to provide you with customer and member support, to perform functions that are described to you at the time of collection, and to enforce our Web Site’s Terms and Conditions. 

We may also use non-personal aggregate information to improve our Web Site. For example, our Internet Service Providers may report to us that there were a particular number of visitors to a certain area of our Web Site, or that a certain number of men or a certain number of women completed our registration form in particular areas of our Web Site. Such information may also be used to analyze the effectiveness of our business and advertising models.

Top opt out of enhanced online display advertising provided directly by Dooney & Bourke, [ Click Here ](http://dtmc.dooney.com/adinfo/choice/prod/?type=fpc&cid=62982&cname=Dooney%20%26%20Bourke&cmagic=b6d843&clogo=62982.png&loc=us&lang=en-us)

## Shared Information 

Dooney.com uses the services of independent companies to provide certain services to you, including, without limitation, Web Site hosting services, credit and debit card processing, order fulfilment, marketing and advertising services, and Internet connectivity services (“Internet Service Providers”). We may share your personal information with the Internet Service Providers as appropriate for purposes relating to the services delivered via our Web Site but not for other purposes.

Occasionally, we make our postal or email mailing list (names and addresses only) and general shopping activity available to select companies whose products we believe will be of interest to you or complementary to our product lines. 

We may also disclose your personal information as is necessary to: (a) comply with a subpoena or court order; (b) cooperate with law enforcement or other government agency; (c) establish or exercise our legal rights; (d) protect the property or safety of our company and employees, contractors, vendors, and suppliers; (e) defend against legal claims; (f) help with internal and external investigations, including protecting against fraud; or (g) as otherwise required by law or permitted by law. We may disclose your information in connection with the sale or merger of Dooney or any transaction that involves the sale or assignment of some or all of our assets. 

We may use a third-party network advertiser to serve the advertisements on the Web Site or may use a traffic measurement service to analyze the traffic on the Web Site. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits to this Web Site and other websites you have visited. Third-party ad serving enables us to target advertisements to you for products or websites you might be interested in. Audience and Traffic Measurement Services allow us to collect anonymous traffic and behavior information from the Web Site by monitoring anonymous visitor activity.

Please visit _[Consumer Opt-out](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp)_ in order to learn more about the information collection practices and "opt-out" procedures of third-party ad servers we may use.

## Links To Third-party Websites

Links on this Web Site may allow you to directly access websites operated by third parties, including, without limitation, our service providers (such as third-party shopping cart service provider) or marketing providers. Some of these third-party marketing channels may be “co-branded” with our logo; even so, these third-party channels are not operated, controlled or maintained by Dooney. These channels or links are provided for your convenience only and should be used with your discretion and prudent judgment. Links from our Web Site to third-party websites do not constitute sponsorship, endorsement, or approval of the content, policies or practices of such third-party websites. The collection and use of your information by such co-branding third parties is the responsibility of the co-branding partner, and they may use your personal information for their direct marketing purposes. We are not responsible for any information these websites or digital channels may obtain and we do not oversee their policies or practices. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information provided to or gathered by the third parties that operate them. The privacy policies of these third-party websites may differ from ours. These websites may ask you for Personal Information. Please review the privacy policy on third-party channels before submitting information, because we do not have control over the use of information collected on these websites. Please review the privacy policies and practices of these digital channels before providing any Personal Information.

## Information Security

Dooney makes reasonable efforts to ensure that our Internet Service Providers have implemented physical, electronic, and procedural security measures to assist with safeguarding your personal information, and to help protect against unauthorized access and disclosure. Only our authorized personnel and our Internet Service Providers who perform legitimate business functions for Dooney are authorized to access your personal information.

Notwithstanding our efforts, the Internet and online services have inherent security risks. Dooney cannot promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information, personal searches, and other communications will always remain secure. You should take care with regard to how you handle and disclose your personal information or any username or password that you are required to use to access services on this Web Site or online service.

## Data Retention Periods

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at privacy@dooney.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. In addition, we may retain and continue to use indefinitely all information contained in your communications to other users of our Web Site posted to public or semi-public areas of the Web Site.

## Other Social Media Websites, and Blogs

The Web Site and the Dooney Mobile application ("Dooney Mobile") may make access to social media sites available to you. You are not required to provide any personal information when using these areas, but you may choose to do so. If you post personal information online, it may become publicly available and you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties. In addition, when you post a comment to some social media sites, your user name and possibly your current location may be made publicly available. By accessing social media sites via the Web Site and Dooney Mobile, you acknowledge that your user name and location information may be disclosed, and that the information you post then becomes subject to the usage terms and privacy policy of the applicable social media site(s); be sure to check those terms and policies. 

We may also offer you the ability to sign in to our Web Site through one or more social networking services. If you do so, any information you supply (or have supplied) to us becomes subject to the privacy policy of that social network/service. We do not control, and are not responsible for, the privacy practices of such networks or services. You should consult the privacy policy of such networks/services. 

We cannot ensure the security of any information you choose to make public on social media sites. Also, we cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information in these areas. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at privacy@dooney.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

## General Audience Web Site Not Directed Toward Children

This Web Site is a general audience Web Site. Our content is neither directed toward minors nor children who are under the age of 13. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. Parents who have questions about personal information that they suspect may have been submitted by a child under the age of 13 should email us at privacy@dooney.com.

## Access to Personal Information and Consent to Transfer

You may notify us at any time if you do not wish us to continue to share your information with our marketing partners (any information previously shared with them may result in continued communications from those parties pursuant to their own privacy policies). You may also notify us if you wish to be removed from our email and postal mailing for our own marketing. To request either form of removal, contact us with your instructions by mail, email or phone or at:

**Dooney & Bourke   
P.O. Box 841  
1 Regent Street, Norwalk, CT 06855

Service@Dooney.com  
(800) 347-5000

**

For those Web Site users located outside the United States, we advise you that your information may be stored and accessible by individuals who are located within the United States. The European Commission and/or other geopolitical regions have determined the United States may not subscribe the same legislative standards for data protection that may be applicable in your place of residence. By providing us with your Personal Information, you are consenting to our use of it in accordance with Dooney’s privacy policy, including the transfer of your information across international boundaries to jurisdictions anywhere in the world as permitted by local law.

## Your California Privacy Rights

Dooney will not share any personal information about you with outside third-parties for their direct marketing purposes to the extent prohibited by California law, unless you agree otherwise as authorized by your prior written consent.

California residents have the right to request information from Dooney regarding the manner that we may share personal information with affiliated companies and third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To find out what and how we share such information, you may send us an e-mail request at privacy@dooney.com or mail a request to: Privacy Officer, Carolyn Donahue, and receive the following information:

  * The categories of information we disclosed to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year, if any;

  * The names and addresses of the third parties who received information for their direct marketing purposes;

  * Examples of the products and services subject to the third-parties’ direct marketing programs, if the nature of the third parties’ business cannot be determined from their names.

## Consent to Privacy Policy

By using the Web Site, you consent to the treatment of our personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will post a notice on the Web Site and/or send an email to users who have provided an email address. Check back periodically for updates. Continued use of this Web Site after an amendment has been posted constitutes agreement to the updated policy.

## Questions About This Privacy Policy

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the privacy practices of this Web Site, please contact us by email at privacy@dooney.com.
